# **Daniel Sawyer**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / DATA SCIENTIST

#### **Profile**

Serious computer scientist with a passion for problem solving, teamwork, and a genuine challenge. I have university research lab level teamwork experience that I believe will transfer over well to industry as I can easily work together with a team while independently solving my piece of the puzzle. I have above average communication skills including public speaking and mentorship, have the capacity to both lead and follow, learn quickly, and work tirelessly until I solve the problem at hand. I can guarantee I will be a good fit wherever I am needed due to my ability to adapt to new and unfamiliar technology quickly, since this is where I tend to thrive.

### **Employment History**

#### TA / RA, University of South Florida, Tampa

AUGUST 2018 - MAY 2022

- Worked on NSF funded M3X project's vision system for automated grasping with robot arm at the USF CARRT lab.
- Worked on object/action recognition in videos for VIRAT and Epic Kitchens challenges.
- Helped teach numerous undergraduate and graduate courses in CSE including Python, Computer Vision, DevOps, and Automata.
- Presentations on research for AI+X seminars at USF.

#### Research Undergrad, University of South Florida, Tampa

JANUARY 2016 - MAY 2018

- Worked on various projects with professors and PhD students.
- NAO robot questions and answers greeter for the CSE department office using Google Assistant Python API and Dialogflow.

#### Education

#### PhD Computer Science, University of South Florida, Tampa

AUGUST 2018 - PRESENT

Taking a leave of absence in order to explore job opportunities.

#### Master of Computer Science, University of South Florida, Tampa

AUGUST 2018 - DECEMBER 2020

• Graduated with a 3.8 GPA.

#### Bachelor of Computer Science, University of South Florida, Tampa

MAY 2015 - MAY 2018

• Graduated cum laude, 3.8 GPA.

## Courses, Projects, Publications

Check CV Link For Courses, Research Projects, and Publications:

https://danielsawyer.com/index.html#cv

#### **Details**

Tampa

United States

813-613-3984

daniel@danielsawyer.com

#### Links

**Homepage** 

GitHub

CV

LinkedIn

#### **Skills**

Python

Anaconda

Deep Learning

PyTorch

TensorFlow

OpenCV

**Bash Scripting** 

CUDA

C++

C#

Java

Swift

Linux Administration

Git

Microsoft Stack

#### Languages

**English** 

French

## References

**Sudeep Sarkar from University of South Florida** sarkar@usf.edu

**Dmitry Goldgof from University of South Florida** goldgof@usf.edu

Larry Hall from University of South Florida lohall@usf.edu